Pritam Shinde

+91 9284574057 | Shinde.Pritam26@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

Summary

I am a Full Stack Developer who is very passionate about application development. I have more than 9.5 years of professional experience working in the Software Industry. I am a seasoned professional, who has the ability to conceptualize, design & implement great products that cater to its fundamental goals. I have helped build products predominantly in Banking, Finance, Securities, and Audit domains. I am most comfortable in web development and aspire to continue to contribute to building amazing products that provide me with professional and personal gratification.

Skill

C#, ASP.Net MVC, .NET Core, WCF, Web API, Entity Framework, Java Script, JQuery, Typescript, Angular, SQL Server, Design Patterns, AWS, Jenkins, Jira, Agile, Scrum, Docker, Git & GitHub, Teamcity, Octopus.

Experience

Volkswagen IT Services, From 05 April 2021 - Till Date

Cognizant Technology, From 06 Jun 2018 - 01 April -2021

LNT Infotech, From 06 Nov 2014 To 04 Jun 2018

Clarion Technology, From 01 Jun 2014 To 03 Nov 2014

Ezacus Technology, From 01 July 2012 To 31 May 2014

Projects Engaged in (VWITS)

- Joined as Team Lead, was assigned to work for Calsium Project.
- Worked on AWS and Angular 8, .Net Core on the go.
- Participated across all the agile ceremonies including Sprint Review, Sprint Retrospective and Sprint Planning.
- Worked on AWS services like EC2, S3, ELB, AutoScalingGroups(ASG), RDS, IAM, Cloud Formation, Route 53, Cloud Watch, Cloud Front, Cloud Trail, Cloud Formation, Elastic Beanstalk.
- Experience in writing effective unit and integration tests.
- Constructing and establishing new development infrastructure and tools.
- Discovering and developing software upgrades and 'fixes' for technical issues.
- Organizing projects and participating in project management decisions.
- Configured **S3 buckets** with various life cycle policies to archive the infrequently accessed data to storage classes based on requirement.
- Used IAM for creating roles, users, groups and also implemented MFA to provide additional security to AWS account and its resources.
- Responsible for performing tasks like Branching, Tagging, and Release Activities on Version Control Tools like GIT.
- Maintained the monitoring and alerting of production and corporate servers using Cloud Watch service.
- Created EBS volumes for storing application files for use with EC2 instances whenever they are

- mounted to them.
- Created snapshots to take backups of the volumes and also images to store launch configurations of the EC2 instances.
- Involved in coding of Web API, MVC using VS 2020, Entity Framework, LINQ, Ninject for dependency injection, Angular Component, Directive, Modules, CSS, JavaScript.
- Role includes end to end development:
 - o Frontend Angular 8, Type Script, HTML
 - o Backend (REST APIs) Web APIs using ASP.NET Core
 - Database Aurora MySQL, Dynamo DB

Projects Engaged in (Cognizant Technology)

- Joined as Senior Software Engineer, was assigned to work for Trading area in LPL Financial.
- Worked on AWS, Angular, MVC, WEB API on the go.
- Participated across all the agile ceremonies including Sprint Review, Sprint Retrospective and Sprint Planning.
- Responsible for performing tasks like Branching, Tagging, and Release Activities on Version Control Tools like TFS.
- Maintained the monitoring and alerting of production and corporate servers using Cloud Watch service.
- Involved in coding of Web API, MVC using VS 2019, Entity Framework, LINQ, Ninject for dependency injection, Angular Component, Directive, Modules, CSS, JavaScript.
- Role includes end to end development:
 - o Frontend Angular 8, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
 - Backend (REST APIs) Web APIs using ASP.NET Core
 - Database MS SQL Server 2016, Dynamo DB

Projects Engaged in (LNT Infotech)

- Joined as Software Engineer and was assigned to work for Investment banking area in **Barclays** ABSA.
- Excellent exposure to Application Level Security as we were building applications for financial trading.
- Working as an onsite coordinator & Involved in all Agile Methodology phases including Sprint Planning, Daily Scrums / Stand Up, Sprint Retrospection.
- Worked on AZURE and Angular 2 on the go.
- Involved in development of WCF Services, Web API, MVC Application.
- Involved in query optimization of query performance using various programming concepts.
- Involved in design write and review of SQL codes (complex stored procedure, function and views) using TRANSACT SQL
- Involved in L3 Support to troubleshoot the production issues and resolving the issues maintaining the SLA's.
- Role includes end to end development:
 - Frontend Angular, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
 - o Backend (REST APIs, WCF) Web API, WCF, MVC.Entity Framework.
 - Database MS SQL Server 2016, Sybase.

Education

Bachelors in Engineering, (Information Technology), Pune University, Pune, India

June 2009 - June 2012, First Class with Distinction, 69 %

Diploma in Engineering, (Information Technology) MSBTE, Mumbai, India

June 2006 - May 2009 First Class, 67 %

Certification

AWS Certified Developer - Associate

Issued by Amazon Web Services Training and Certification



Communication

F 907, Mantra Moments, Moshi Pune, India.